Welcome to building your network marketing business
with Jim Rohn. Mr. Rohn has been
hailed over the years as one of the
most influential thinkers of our time as well
as a major influence to an entire
generation of personal development trainers and speakers.
Jim has been described as a master motivator
by Mark Victor Hansen, a national treasure by
Vic Conant, one of the most profound
thinkers and mind-expanding individuals of our time by
Les Brown, and an extraordinary human being and
mentor by Anthony Robbins. Jim Rohn has been
sharing his success philosophies and principles for
over 37 years with more than 5,000 audiences
and 3 million people worldwide. He is the
recipient of the coveted CPAE award from the National
Speakers Association for Excellence in Speaking and is
the author of over 18 books, audio, and
video programs.
So now, let the man who has influenced so many
help you to invent your future. Here's Mr. Jim Rohn.
It is so much fun to travel the world, especially
for me, farm boy from Idaho. I didn't have many
skills when I first awakened to the opportunity that
you know you could work for pay. I knew how
to milk cows but you know that was about it
and it didn't pay very well. But when I was introduced
to network marketing, health and nutrition, a
marketing system where I could start at the
top and start part-time, it literally revolutionized and
changed my life forever. I've never been the
same. And a big share of my story now
is sharing with people around the world this extraordinary
opportunity. And then along with it, the philosophy
that makes it work. Because you can have every
technique in the world and the best product in
the world and you can have the finest support system
in the world, but unless you
have the philosophy that drives you
to make it work, then nothing works. So I like to
talk about all the things that made it work for me
and see if that might not be valuable for someone
else. So I want you to take some good notes. If
you're ready to take notes, say, I'm ready. I like
this crowd already. Treat me well, I might take you
with me as my traveling audience. Now here's the
next key on being prepared for the next century.
And that is your personal philosophy.
Celebrate the best Pacific Island tropical
travel tour.
She should have died at least 20 years earlier than she did
simply because she stretched out those years by the study of good nutrition
I was an only child and mama studied and you know
mixed up all that stuff back then, you know, she'd say hey
Me and Papa and her she said drink this stuff if
it don't kill us. I think it'll help, you know, and we're
Gagging down this stuff
And mama taught all of that
but the payoff was so incredible I
Passed it on to my two daughters. They've never
been ill. They passed it on to their children
My grandchildren that haven't been ill
I mean the study of good nutrition paying attention and being
involved in the industry you're in it's one of the best so
That's so important your personal philosophy
What you believe in?
That's gonna carry you into the next century
Let me give you now some of the early philosophies that
changed my life forever. I heard one of them in my introduction
Some of these philosophies have lived with me now
All of these years I've passed them on
and people have come back around saying Mr.
Rohn, you know 10 years ago 20
years ago 30 years ago 35 years ago
I sat in your class and sat in your seminar and those
early things that you taught I've practiced it and I'm doing it a
Man not long ago showed me notes. He took 23
years ago, and then he had me sign those notes
He said I've used these notes to develop my life my
personal life and my business life and when he took those notes
He said I was 18 years old
So it's incredible
I'm so thankful for
All these years, but now I want to pass it along
to you some of the philosophies that changed my life forever
Okay, if you're ready say I'm ready
Here's the first one
Profits are better than wages
Once I understood that I got rich
Nobody taught me that in high school. I
Went to college for a year and
a half and I never heard it
I'm 25 and broke
I'm not destitute. I'm broke too much month
at the end of the money is broke and
I finally hear this philosophy profits are better than wages
Now here's the phrase that goes with it
wages make you a living which is fine
profits make you a fortune which is super fine and
You can live both fine and super fine. You've now
got the mechanism and the ways means to do that
Profits are better than wages. Guess
what I taught this in Moscow
when I was teaching capitalism
You know, the Communists had it all wrong
They taught that capitalism was, you know a big company
that oppresses its workers. I mean, it was absolutely ridiculous
They had mentally lost it when
they came up with this ridiculous philosophy
Now communism taught capital belongs to the state not the people and
we taught all these years what capital belongs in the hands of
the people not to stay
That's why of course kids should pay taxes because
they can be capitalists and all capitalists should pay taxes
And it doesn't take much to start
an enterprise that makes a profit. I
Teach kids how to have two bicycles one to ride and
one to rent. I mean, you know, how long does it take?
How long does it take to make a profit?
I mean a little ingenuity and you're on your way
So profits are better than
wages capitalism better than communism
Communism said people are too dumb and stupid
To know what to do with capital so
you must take capital away from all the dumb
stupid people and give it
to the all-wise all-knowing state and
Let the state run everything. I mean that was communism and
they devastated every country they touched. I've been to East Germany
It's taking a trillion dollars
just to clean up East Germany
They've already spent 500 billion. They
got 500 billion more to go. I
mean
Every country they touched and
I've been in all of them
They devastated them all with their devastating philosophy. We
teach capital belongs in the hands of the people
that's where the ingenuity is to bring goods and services to
the marketplace and I'm going to show you later the miracle of
capitalism grassroots in America, which you're involved in
But once I understood this now, it was so incredible
Profits are better than wages. Now when I first
was recruited. I'm a distributor for this little project
I'm a distributor for this
little product called a bunda vita
And here's what my mentor said
Mr. Shove
He said mr. Own you can start this
miracle working business part-time
You don't have to go full-time you can start part-time and he said
if you'll devote to start with let's say 10 12 15 hours a week
Where you'll start making a profit?
Here's what you can now say
I'm working full-time on my job
and part-time on my four-day job
I'm working full-time on my four-day job
Because profits lead to fortune I
Got so excited about that philosophy. I'm working full-time on
my job, but now I'm working part-time on my fortune I
Found a way not only to make a living you
won't believe this I found a way to make a fortune
Can you imagine what that's like
then to get up in the morning
To go to work on your fortune not
to go to work to pay the rent
Which is okay
But a chance to go to work to
make a fortune and I said right now
I'm working part-time on my fortune and full-time on my job, but
it won't be long until I'll be working full-time on my fortune
Can you imagine what life is gonna be like?
Now here was my first goal when
I started and that was part-time I
Wanted to equal on my profits part-time
what I was earning on my full-time job
This is called the magic of part-time. It is
so thrilling for people to start working the business part-time
Because now you can work on
profits and it doesn't take very long
If you'll really concentrate on those
10 12 15 hours a week
It won't be long if you really do
it right and learn some of the skills
I'm going to talk about it won't be
long until you can be earning as much
Part-time working on your fortune as you are full-time working
on your job. I did that in less than six months
Now I've got an incredible invitation
I
Found a way part-time to work on my fortune and I'm making
as much money at that as I am on my full-time job
Would you like to hear my story?
It was incredible
Now here was my second goal
To make twice as much money part-time
Working on my fortune as I
was working full-time on my job
And I reached that in less than a year
Making twice as much money part-time working on my
fortune as I was full-time working on my job
Now I've got an incredible invitation that won't quit I
found a way
Through a unique opportunity to work part-time on my fortune
and I'm now earning twice as much money as I am
Working full-time on my job. Would
you like to hear my story?
Do you imagine anybody would say no,
I don't care to hear your story. No
Everybody I said that to said wow. Yes. What are you
doing? I said, I'm glad you asked. Let me tell you
Now when I started making twice as much money part-time as
full-time, here's here's my dilemma. I didn't want to go full-time and
Why not go full-time and the reason was
because I didn't want to give up my
electrifying story
Right, it was so powerful
Nobody could resist the invitation
to at least take a look
I didn't want to give it up and I hung on for
I don't know how long until it was, you know, almost insane
Then finally finally
Reluctantly, I gave up my full-time job
But now
You can see me my
junction will just like a other不会
That the total amount of genius I did this late
I've never felt before I thought I was you
I don't doubt that
She just got away from home
I'm surprised that she landed her first job
But now you can imagine the thrill and
excitement of going to work full-time on my fortune
It was incredible
But I want you to
jot down the magic of part-time
and here's what the change in lifestyle does.
It's a great recruiting tool.
One of the greatest recruiting attractions
is the money you make part-time.
Somebody said, you've been on three vacations this year?
Says, yes, I got this little part-time thing going.
Says, what's that?
You bought two new cars, one
for you and one for her?
How did you do that?
Said, I got this little part-time thing going.
Your kids have got all these new clothes?
Yes.
All this stuff is happening?
What is it?
An extra thousand a month.
See, a thousand a month full-time,
nobody wants to hear your story.
A thousand a month part-time
that starts to change your lifestyle,
everybody wants to hear your story.
So the key is part-time.
The magic and the attraction of part-time
gives you a classic invitation
for somebody to listen to what you're doing
that's changing your life.
And it's not just necessarily the money
that changes your life.
It's what you do.
It's what you do with the money.
It's the change of lifestyle.
So part-time helps to change lifestyle,
which gives you a classic invitation
to look at what you're doing.
That's how I started in network marketing.
Age 25.
Wow, these philosophies changed my life.
I wish I would have learned them in high school.
In high school, if they would have offered wealth one,
wealth two, I'd have taken both classes.
I wouldn't have waited until I was 25 and broke.
Here's the next one.
Philosophy that helped change my life.
It's not what happens that determines your life future.
It's what you do about what happens.
All of us are in like a little sailboat.
And it's not the blowing of the wind
that determines your destination.
It's the set of the sail.
So jot this phrase down.
It's one of the best to understand.
Kids need to understand it.
The same wind blows on us all.
The wind of disaster, the wind of opportunity,
the wind of change, the wind when it's upside down,
the wind when it's favorable and unfavorable.
The same wind blows on us all.
The economic wind, the social wind, the political wind,
the same wind blows on everybody.
The difference in where you arrive in one year,
three years, five years, the difference in arrival
is not the blowing of the
wind, but the set of the sail.
And that's what learning is all about.
To set a better sail this year than last year.
To set a better sail.
The first six years of my
economic life, I wound up broke.
Second six years, I wound up rich.
You say, well, the Democrats must have finally gotten power.
No, no, no.
It was not a political change.
Here's what changed the second
six years of my economic life.
It was my philosophy that changed.
The set of the sail of better thinking,
correcting the errors of the people,
the past and picking up new disciplines for the future.
That's all I had to do
at the end of the first six.
Correct the errors of the past
and then pick up some new disciplines for the future.
And my total life changed.
The second six years was totally different
than the first six of my working life.
And guess who can do that?
Anybody.
Now you can keep on the same path
for the next couple of years
as you have the past two.
But if you wish to, if you wish to,
and maybe everything's okay for
you and you don't need to,
but if you need to
make some changes, I'm telling you,
you can start doing it today
so that the next two years will be drastically different
than the last two.
And anybody who wishes to do that can.
And you can do it between ages 40 and 43.
You can do it between ages 13 and 15.
You can do it between ages 60 and 62.
Any two years, any five years
that you wish to drastically change from the previous five,
you can do it.
If you wish to.
Now this isn't written, this is not a law.
Here's what it's called, opportunity.
But if you don't know you can change,
if you don't know you can drastically change your income,
change your future, change your health,
change your marriage, change everything.
If you don't know that,
some people then go year
after year after year after year,
not making much change
simply because they didn't get to the class.
They never read the book.
They never went to the seminar.
They never made the discovery.
They didn't seek for the knowledge
of how could I make my life better?
And if you just rock
along, I'm telling you it's okay.
Anybody can live any way they choose,
but I'm here to tell all
of you that if you wish to,
it's possible to make the next three years
totally different than the last three.
And all you have to
do is just a few things.
So we've got that one now,
it's not the blowing of the wind
that determines your income.
It's not the blowing of the wind
that determines your fortune.
It's the set of the sail.
And that's why we gathered here today.
Maybe I've got some ideas that'll help you
with a couple of little things about setting the sail
of your thinking that might,
that might drastically give you multiplied more benefit
the next three years than
you've gotten in the last three.
So it's not what happens.
What happens, happens to everybody.
Chevron years ago brought me in to talk to management.
They said, Mr. Rohn, you travel around the world
and you're fairly knowledgeable.
What do you think the next
10 years are gonna be like?
I said, gentlemen, I can tell you,
I do know the right people.
So they all lean forward and listen carefully.
And I said, gentlemen, the
next 10 years are gonna be
about like the last 10.
The next season after fall is?
I promise you that's not gonna change.
After day comes?
Night.
I promise you that's not gonna change.
Here's how the last 6,000 years reads.
If you want to make a
note of Jim Rohn's vision of history,
the last 6,000 years, here's how it reads.
Opportunity mixed with difficulty.
And if we're around another 6,000 years,
it's gonna read like that looks like
for the next 6,000 years.
Opportunity mixed with?
Difficulty.
Now, sometimes there seems to be more opportunity
than difficulty.
And then sometimes there seems to be more difficulty
than opportunity, but the mix isn't gonna change.
After expansion comes?
Recession.
But!
Recession comes?
Expansion.
Not to think so, see, is naive.
And once you've got just
a little of this stuff settled,
then you know exactly what to do.
You know exactly what to
anticipate so you can be ready.
Now, here's the next one and
I heard it in my invitation.
Here's what it says.
For things to change, you have to change.
I was hoping the government would change
and taxes would change and economics would change
and my boss would change and be more generous.
I wished for everything to change and my teacher said,
I wish for everything to change and my teacher said,
No, Mr. Owen, for things to change for you,
you have to change.
Don't wish it was easier, wish you were better.
Once I understood this, this
altered the course of my life.
Don't wish it was easier, wish you were better.
And here's the big one.
Don't wish for less problems, wish for more skills.
You don't need less problems.
You simply need more skills.
Don't wish for less challenge, wish for more success.
Don't wish for more wisdom.
Accept the challenge because you
can't grow without a challenge.
You can't get rich without a challenge.
You can't fly without gravity.
You have to understand the challenge.
But that's the key is to
now develop wisdom to overcome the challenge.
Don't wish for less challenge, but more wisdom.
And then here's one more philosophy
to help change my life forever.
You can do the most
remarkable things no matter what happens.
Humans can do the most remarkable things no matter what.
Happens.
Philosophies that change my life.
Here's one of the big
philosophies I learned in network marketing.
It's called the law of averages.
If you do something often enough, a ratio will appear.
Key phrase, if you do something
often enough, a ratio will appear.
It's amazing. It's uncanny.
In baseball, we call it batting average.
If you talk to 10 people, one says yes.
Now the ratio has begun.
One out of 10.
Talk to 10, get one.
Here's something interesting about the law of averages.
Once it starts, it tends to continue.
This is colossal information.
Once a ratio starts, it tends to continue.
If you talk to 10 and get one, sure enough, chances
are excellent if you talk to 10 more, you'll get another one.
Talk to 10 more.
You'll get another one.
Now you can compete.
If you can only get one
out of 10, you can compete.
Even with somebody that can get nine out of 10.
If you've been here a long time,
you can get nine out of 10.
I just joined. I can
only get one out of 10.
If we have a 30-day contest, I will beat you.
Say, well, how could you beat me?
Here's why.
During that 30 days, you
talk to 10 and get nine.
I talk to 100 and get 10.
I beat you.
Isn't that clever?
This is clever stuff.
And I do it for two reasons.
I sincerely wish to win.
But I do it for another very sincere reason.
I wish for you to lose.
And that's noble on my part.
Here's why it's noble.
You learn more by losing than you do by winning.
So I wish to give you that experience.
Now here's how I do it
once I understand the law of averages.
When I'm new,
I'm new.
I make up in numbers what I lack in skill.
Now who can do that?
Anybody that's ambitious.
Anybody with a little ingenuity.
Anybody.
Doesn't matter.
Now here's one more.
The law of averages can be increased.
You get one out of 10.
Talk to 10, get another one.
The fourth time you talk to 10, you get two.
Why would the...
The fourth time you talk to
10, you get two instead of one.
You're getting better.
And who can get better?
Anybody.
Talk to 10, get two.
Finally, talk to 10, get three.
I finally got up to about three.
Now it takes more than a genius
to go past like three or four.
But three will do.
If you bat 300 in baseball,
they pay you $4 million a year.
Which means you're out seven times out of 10.
Seven times out of 10, out.
Make $4 million a year.
Are you ready for that?
So this works so well now in your business.
Just jot the phrase down.
You don't have to bat 1,000.
You don't have to bat 1,000 to make big money.
You don't have to bat $1,000 to make big money.
One out of 10 is fine.
Two out of 10 is terrific.
Three out of 10 is fabulous.
Some particular incredible genius might get four out of 10.
But three out of 10 is sufficient
to make you rich beyond your wildest imagination.
This is how I went after my friends,
neighbors, and relatives when I first started recruiting.
I said, look, I've got a new business and
I'm getting about three out of 10 to join.
And I don't mind you.
Just come to the meeting
and be one of the seven.
It doesn't matter.
You're my friend.
You'll do me a favor.
And so it's not important
to me that you like it.
It's not important to me that you join.
It's certainly not important to me that you buy.
It's just important to me that you listen.
One of the reasons, though, I want you to hear the
story is because a year from now, if I'm doing well,
I don't want you to say, how come
you never picked up the phone a year ago?
I never got a letter, never got a call.
You call me a friend.
You're making all this money.
You never picked up the phone.
So I don't want that to happen.
So for two reasons, I want
you to see what I'm doing.
So the year from now, if I'm doing well,
I can say, you know, I gave you the opportunity.
But also just as a favor,
come and be one of the seven.
It doesn't matter to me if you buy or join.
But I need 10 to get three.
And if you're one of the three, wonderful.
If you're not, wonderful.
It doesn't.
It might matter to you.
It might matter to you,
but it doesn't matter to me.
Now, it matters to me because we're friends,
but it doesn't matter in terms of my averages.
So if you decide to get
rich, just learn the law of averages.
You're off and running.
Now, here's the second law that
changed my life forever in network marketing.
I learned the law of sowing and reaping.
And in the law of sowing and reaping
is also the story of the law of averages.
Jot this down.
The story of the sower.
Comes from the.
Bible.
I'm an amateur on the Bible,
but this is such a useful story.
Here's what the story says.
And take the notes because
the drama is in the details.
The sower was ambitious.
Evidently, he was ambitious.
When you read the whole story, you'll conclude.
Yes, this was an ambitious sower.
Here was number two.
He had excellent seed.
The sower who sowed the seed had excellent seed.
And the excellent seed can be an
excellent opportunity, an excellent product, an excellent story.
So we've got an ambitious sower with.
Excellent seed.
But now here's the rest
of the details of the story.
For your information, for the drama of your life.
So you can understand things better.
Learning some of this is how
I got rich by age 31.
Okay.
Number one, it says the sower goes out to
sow the seed, but the first part of the seed
falls by the wayside and the birds get it.
So jot this down.
The birds are going to get some of the seed.
The.
Now you say, well, Mr.
What does that mean?
Well, I invite John to come to a meeting.
He said he'd be there Tuesday night.
Tuesday night.
I show up.
John isn't there.
I say, John, I wonder why John didn't make it.
Now I know the answer.
The birds.
John had this great idea of coming
to the meeting to look at an opportunity.
And somebody.
Stole it.
And said, you're not going to go see network marketing.
And he says, well, maybe not.
So have you jot that down now?
The birds are going to get some.
Now when the birds get some, you've got two options.
Number one is to chase birds.
And say, well, let me get ahold of the person
that talked to him out of coming to the meeting.
I'll tear him a new
page, but I wouldn't do this.
I wouldn't do this.
I'd hate to do this.
Here's what happens if you go
chasing birds, you leave the field.
If you go chasing birds, now you leave the field.
Which is going to distract from your future, not add.
So you can't chase birds and
try to straighten this stuff out.
Here's what it is.
It's just one of those things.
And here's the best comment
when things are a little disappointing.
Isn't that interesting?
You just, you just have to say,
I thought sure he would be there.
He would be there.
He promised me.
But I know it was the birds.
And you just have to say, isn't that interesting?
Now here's the rest of the story.
It says the sower kept on sowing.
See that was the secret to his success.
He kept on sowing.
And if you keep sowing, you can sow more
than the birds can get because there aren't enough
birds.
If you keep sowing, there are some birds,
but there's not enough because the law of
averages will work for you.
My mentor taught me.
He said, you know, Mr. Rohn.
There's only nine or 10 real
nasty, miserable people in the whole world.
Now he says they move around a lot, you
know, and you're liable to, you'll bump into one
once in a while, but when you bump into
one, you say there's only nine more like you.
I can handle that in the whole world.
Okay.
Now here's what else it says.
The sower now keeps sowing the seed.
Now the seed falls.
The story says on rocky ground where the soil is.
Shallow and the rocky ground where the soil
is shallow is not of your making because you
had excellent seed and you were an ambitious sower.
So the rocky ground where the soil is shallow
is not of your making, but here's what it
says.
What happened this time?
The little seed that falls in the ground starts
to grow and the little plant starts to grow,
but the first hot day it withers and dies.
It does not an easy thing to watch.
I finally get John started.
Sure enough, three or four days
later, somebody says, boom, and he goes,
he's gone.
Doesn't show up at the second meeting.
And I say, I thought
sure John had last a week.
What happened?
Jot this down.
He's gone.
And he's gone.
And you've had something.
Now the sun is going to get on him.
The hot weather is going to get
some, and this is not of your making.
Here's what you must say.
When that happens, isn't that interesting.
Wow, what can you do?
The answer is nothing.
You say, well, I'm going to try to change this.
I wouldn't take that class.
You know, the sun comes up in
the east, somebody says, why is that?
I wouldn't spend much time on that.
Just let that happen.
Don't go for this.
Don't go for this why, why, why stuff.
I'm giving you the answers here.
The answers is in the structure
and the consequences and in the deal.
The answer is in the deal.
Anything beyond that is not worth studying.
You say, well, how come
some just last a little while?
I wouldn't sign up for that class.
Here's the answer.
Some don't stay.
You just have to jot that down.
And when some leaves, you say,
that's one of those that don't stay.
Now you know what category to put them in.
And you can't solve this now.
It's like rearranging the seasons.
You can't fool with that.
All you can do is cooperate
with the way things are set up.
I didn't set it up.
You say, well, it shouldn't be this way.
Well, when you get your own
planet, you can rearrange this whole deal.
But on this planet, you're a guest.
You've got to take it as it comes.
Now, here was the secret to
the ambitious sower with good seed.
It said he kept.
On.
Sowing.
Now, here's what he had
to do to keep on sowing.
He had to discipline his disappointment.
This is a key phrase now
to use the rest of your life.
You must learn to discipline your disappointment.
Because you didn't set up the setup.
And some are not going to stay.
And that is not of your making.
Now, if you made gross errors and
you ran them off, see, that'd be different.
Now, you're responsible for that.
But if it's in the normal course
of things, this is the way things are.
Now, here's what it says.
The sower keeps on sowing.
Now, it says the seed falls on thorny ground.
And somebody says, well, how much of
this do you have to go through?
Well, hang on.
It's not the end of the story now.
Now, the little seed falls on thorny ground.
And now, the little plant starts to grow again.
But as the little plant starts to
grow, the thorns choke it to death.
And it dies.
So, jot this down.
The thorns are going to get some.
And that's not of your making.
And what are these thorns?
The story even called these little
thorns, little cares, little distractions, little somethings.
Who knows what all they are?
I say, John, we had a meeting last night.
You weren't here.
John says, well, I can't make every meeting.
I say, why not?
You're part time.
He said, well, the screen door came off the hinges.
And you just can't let your house fall apart.
You got to take some time and fix things up.
And I can hear the thorns going, uh-uh.
He says, some extra trash
had piled up in the garage.
You can't let mountains of trash take over.
You got to keep your trash hauled out.
People who let little things
cheat them out of big opportunities.
And you feel almost helpless.
What could I do about that?
And that's nothing.
And you say, well, why is this?
I'm asking you not to sign up.
For that class.
Don't sign up for these.
Why is this class?
It's just the way it is.
Like winter following fall and spring following.
So if you got that, the
thorns are going to get some.
But now here's the good news.
Let's read the rest of the story now quickly.
The sower now what?
Keeps on sowing the seed.
Keeps on sharing the story.
Keeps on giving an invitation.
Yes, the invitation can be more powerful for me as
it was one year later than it was the first.
The first month.
Because now I'm saying I'm making twice as much money
part time as I'm making on my full time job.
Yes, the story can be more powerful.
But the law of average is still going to work.
But now here's what the story said.
Finally, the seed falls on good ground.
Now put this in parenthesis.
It always will.
If you keep sowing.
If you share a good idea long enough.
It will fall on good people.
But now here's the rest of that story.
Some of the good ground did 30 percent.
And some of the good ground did.
60 percent.
100 percent.
You say, well, why the difference in numbers?
I wouldn't sign up for that class.
Come on.
Have I said that often enough now?
Don't register for that class.
It's just the way it is.
Now I tried to get the 30s to do 60.
Found out it was more than I could handle.
I used to say, I'll make
them successful if it kills me.
I almost died.
No, you can't do that.
Here's what you do.
Let the 30s do 30 to the best of their ability and keep doing 30
because that's how they build their lifestyle and get what they want out of life.
And let the 60s do 60
and let the 100s do 100s.
Now, how can you get some to do 100%?
You got to go through all these experiences
and you got to talk to all these people.
Let me quickly give you now a list
of the skills that changed my life forever.
Developing a new philosophy that I could do it.
In my network marketing experience now
led me to developing new skills.
Right. I knew how to
milk cows, but didn't pay well.
Here's the first skill I learned to change my life.
Getting a customer.
Making a sale.
And of course, sales for you is easy, right?
Because it's not technical, right?
The technical is all taken care of.
You simply represent your product.
If you share a unique product.
Talk about its merits.
Persuade someone that it's the best.
They agree to buy.
That's the simple art of sales.
But in your business, here's what it's more like.
Sharing.
Because using the product yourself, gathering
some testimonials, you simply share that.
So we're not talking like
high-powered spacecraft technical skills here.
It's simply sharing something
you've discovered with someone else.
And doing it well enough to where they agree.
They would like to.
Participate.
Now here's what happened when I learned sales.
It multiplied my income by five.
Now it didn't take that much because
I wasn't doing that well in farm country.
But it did multiply my income by five.
Sales.
Getting customers.
Laying that incredible foundation
for an entrepreneurial career.
So now I've got two skills.
Milking cows and making sales.
And I've got a business opportunity.
Here's the next one I learned that changed me forever.
And that's recruiting.
Introducing the business opportunity to new people.
Learning how to give a good invitation.
Learning how to give two kinds of presentation.
Formal and informal.
And the third part of
recruiting of course is following up.
Once you start a new life, now
you've got to take care of it.
Like a new mother would take care of her baby.
You don't start a new life and abandon it.
You start a new life and
nourish it like a mother in particular.
And that's what I learned.
And I'm going to tell you a story.
I'm going to tell you a story.
You don't be a mother
and protect it like a father.
You've got to be both mother and father
to a new person.
Nourishment ideas like a mother.
Protection help defend to your new life.
Against the encroachment of outside voices .
That would try to talk them out of it.
So you gotta be mother and father.
In this art of recruiting.
We call it being a sponsor.
And being the sponsors like being the bridge.
Helping somebody from darkness to light.
From skeptic to faith.
From not knowing to knowing.
Being a sponsor's like being a bridge.
From no confidence in themselves
to starting to gain confidence.
You're the bridge that helps people
from the shadows to the sunlight.
It's one of the most exciting positions
to occupy in all of network marketing industry.
Is the bridge helping people crossing
the bridge out from discouragement into recognition.
Being this bridge, that's what
the recruiting magic is all about.
You've got the answers.
They've been looking for the answers.
And you help them cross this bridge.
You see something in them before
they can see it in themselves.
You assure them that it's possible
to be more than they are.
Therefore, they can earn more than
they've got, have more than they possess.
This is one of the great arts in the world.
And here's what's exciting about this art.
It pays big money.
Because now you operate a unique
philosophy taught first in the Bible.
John Kennedy taught it in his inaugural speech.
Zig Ziglar's got one of the best.
And that's the secret to wealth.
The secret to wealth and fortune.
First taught in the Bible.
Because the question was asked,
how can we achieve greatness?
Great wealth, great power, great
influence, great recognition, great self-esteem.
How can we achieve greatness?
The master teacher was asked.
And here was his formula for achieving personal greatness.
He said, find a way to serve the many.
For service to many.
Leads to greatness.
For those that are interested.
Some people aren't interested.
But for those that are.
Service to many leads to greatness.
Someone says, well, best I can
do is just take care of myself.
Which is okay.
But it doesn't lead to greatness.
Somebody says, I got enough bills of my own.
I can't worry about someone else's bills.
That's okay.
But it doesn't lead to greatness.
Greatness is helping people pay their bills.
You forget about yours.
Because if you help enough
people pay theirs, yours disappear.
Help people with problems.
Your problems disappear.
The key to greatness, the master
teacher taught, is finding a way.
Now, a lot of people would like to
serve many people, but they don't have a way.
And what's exciting about you and your
business is you've now got the way.
Whether you use it or not, it's up to you.
Whether you cash it in
or not is up to you.
Whether you make a fortune or just a little.
That's all up to you.
Each person's ambition.
It's called the same marketing.
The same product.
Products are the same for everybody.
The marketing system is the same.
The difference is each person's
philosophy and each person's individual ambition.
But whatever your ambitions are, now
you've got the ways and means.
And here's what you've got
the ways and means to do.
Serve as many people as you would like.
Now, here's what's exciting about recruiting.
With what you're involved in here, you can directly
and indirectly affect the lives of dozens of people.
Some of you are going to directly and
indirectly affect the lives of hundreds of people.
And some of you, if you wish, can directly
and indirectly affect the lives of thousands of people.
And the pay is accordingly.
If you affect a few, you earn that pay.
If you affect the many, you earn that pay.
But the secret is found in the Bible.
Service to many leads to greatness.
Now, John Kennedy said it in his inaugural speech.
Here's what he said.
Don't ask.
Don't we wish that was the current political philosophy?
Where is John Kennedy and his philosophy?
John Kennedy said, don't ask.
That's important if you understand philosophy.
He said, don't ask what
the people can do for you.
Don't ask what the country can do for you.
Don't ask what the government can do for you.
That's not how you get rich.
That's not how you have high self-esteem.
That's not how you get trophies to
put on the mantle above the fireplace.
Asking what the people can do for you.
Don't ask, he said, what
the people can do for you.
But ask.
What could I do for my country?
And the country means the people.
What could I do for the people?
I want trophies.
I want recognition.
I want high self-esteem.
I would even like a chance to make a fortune.
John Kennedy said it's easy.
Don't ask what the people can do for you.
But ask, what could I do for the people?
Could I directly and indirectly serve many in my country?
And now that you are participating
in this program, the answer is yes.
I'm going to ask you a question.
Now, Zig probably said it best.
Zig's got some great stuff.
Zig and I have been good
friends for a lot of years.
Zig says money isn't everything, but
it ranks right up there with oxygen.
Zig, you're right.
Zig says my dentist told me, Zig,
only floss the teeth you want to keep.
You know, forget the rest.
But here, Zig is famous for this now.
This is one of Zig's philosophies, and it goes right
along with the other two, the Bible and John Kennedy.
Here's what Zig says.
If you help enough people get what
they want, you can have everything you want.
Now, wanting everything you
want, we call that self-interest.
But it's okay to have self-interest if
you do it in a positive way.
By helping enough people get what they
want, you can have everything you want.
Now, you can accomplish all that
by learning this next skill called recruiting.
And I learned it, and it made me fortunate.
So now I've got three skills.
Milking cows, making sales, and recruiting.
Here's the next skill I learned that paid big money.
Organizing.
Once you got a few, get them
to work together, see, and that's magic.
Getting people to work together is magic.
Now, yes, it's challenging, like having several members
of your family getting them to work together.
It's challenging.
But everything다는 is challenging.
Getting husband and wife to work together is challenging.
but it's magic when it happens.
But everything magic is challenging.
Just gotta jot that down.
Everything magic is challenging.
But once you figure out the challenge
and go for it, then the magic occurs.
Let me tell you how magical people working together is.
Let me quote the Bible again.
It says, if two or three agree
on a common purpose, nothing is impossible.
Just try that on for your mental size.
It's a great idea to do that when if you
start talking to people in the classroom and they're you.
Just try that on for your mental size.
If two or three agree
on a common purpose, nothing's impossible.
Everybody's looking for a challenge.
Here's what I teach, especially the kids.
Here's the best challenge in the world.
Let's go do it.
Not you go do it.
If two or three of us decide on
a common purpose to do it, nothing's impossible.
Incredible.
Working together, organizing.
Now, when everybody's an independent,
now it's a little more challenging.
Like having kids, they've each got their own opinions.
They've each got their own ambitions and desires.
It's challenging.
You've got a variety.
But that's what makes life the variety.
And in your business, it is
challenging, getting people to work together.
It's like herding cats.
You know, sheep are easy.
Sheep are easy.
But you've got to try cats, herding cats.
But if you can possibly get
it done, the power is so immense.
When you get people to work together.
Here's one of the powers of working together.
Shared testimonials.
If I've got somebody new and you're there
and I'm there, I give them my testimonial.
You give your testimonial.
Maybe what tips the scales in getting me a
new person is not my testimonial, but my partner's testimonial.
Somebody I'm working with.
Their testimonial got them.
Shared testimonials are so powerful.
That's why getting working together is okay.
It's powerful.
Now, working by yourself is okay.
All this stuff is okay.
Everybody needs to know.
So where are the advantages?
And these are some of the advantages.
I learned to organize, paid big money.
Here's what I next learned to do.
Promote.
Promotion now pays staggering money.
Now, the company comes up
with what we call major promotions.
Here's what you've got to come up with.
The smaller promotions.
The company comes up with major recognition.
You've got to come up with
small recognition for your people around you.
The top five.
The company's got top five.
You've got your own.
You've got your own top five
in maybe two or three categories.
Top five, top five, top five.
And those little recognitions.
To reach certain levels in the
company, you have to take major steps.
But for you, recognition, let them take small steps.
Here's one of the secrets of your kind of business.
Rewarding people for small steps of progress.
Rewarding people.
Sometimes it's just recognition.
Handshake.
Pat on the back.
Mary, you're doing a fabulous job.
And you figure out what those recognitions are.
Small steps of progress.
Guess what promotion pays if you learn it well?
Big money.
Getting people to do something
they wouldn't ordinarily do by themselves.
People will do some unique things by themselves.
But if you can figure out a way to say, Mary, if
you do this and this, she says, well, I'll go for it.
Now, she wouldn't have thought of that on her own.
Here's what works magic.
It's better than money.
Money is a bit unimportant.
Here's what's important.
Ingenuity.
The best thing about money
is that it's not about money.
It's about the money.
And the best place to wake up
your ingenuity is what you're doing right now.
Representing a unique product and getting customers,
recruiting distributors and promoting and all this stuff.
Ingenuity.
Figuring out a way.
If it doesn't work this way, we'll work another way.
I used my ingenuity and made a fortune.
My ingenuity worked on doing all these campaigns.
The spring campaign and the
summer campaign and the winter campaign.
This week we're going to recruit school teachers.
How many of you got it?
This is school teacher research.
week, school teacher month. I'd pick out a
little category and say, let's go for it.
And it doesn't matter what it is. Just dream
up something so that somebody's got a little more
objective to go for than just their own. Key
phrase, we all need to belong to something bigger
than ourselves. Because we furnish inspiration
for what's bigger and the bigger furnishes
inspiration for us. I learned promotion and it
paid big money. Here's next I learned, communication.
How to conduct a meeting. I learned
identification, logic and reason, attack and confess,
solution. Simple deals on communication. Wasn't easy for me
at first. I stood up to give my first
presentation, my mind sat back down. Right? Y'all
been through that? Opened my mouth, nothing came
out for a while. But here's what I did. I did
it again. Just jot that phrase down. I did it again.
That's the secret to how I
got here. 35, 40 years later.
That's how I got here. I did it
once. It was uncomfortable. That first presentation was so
lousy. If I hadn't have been doing it, I'd have
gone home. It was not that good. But here's the
secret to how I got here. I did it again. And then
I did it again. And then I did it again. And I did
it again. I remember when I first decided to
be a little more animated, right? And walk out away
from the podium, right? Get out from just behind the
podium. So I got out there and then I thought,
how do you get the...
Get back. Whoa, I'm stranded out here. Remember
those times? Doing something for the first time?
But you learn quickly in your business, right? In
your business, a guy stands up to give his
first testimonial and he's so nervous, he forgets his
own name, right? And 30 days later, he wants
to give a three-hour testimonial, right? You can
hardly get him off the stage. So learn communication.
How to affect other people with words. That's
the greatest art in the world to learn.
How to affect other people with words.
Key phrase, don't be lazy in language.
If you learn to use the gift of your own
language wisely, it can make you a fortune and build an
incredible life. Here's three other things I
learned. One is to train. Training people how
the business works. And then I've used another
word called teach, train and teach. And only to
say this, training people how the business works,
teaching is how life works. Because here's what all
of us need to do. We need to be able to
teach people how the business works. And that's what I'm doing.
We need to be able to teach people
how the business works. And that's what I'm doing.
We need for the 21st
century, business skills and life skills.
The life skills are leadership skills. The
life skills are learning how to set goals.
Now here's the ultimate skill to learn that can
transform your life and the life of whoever will
listen. The ability to inspire. Inspire means help
people to look up a little higher than where
they are and wish they could get
there and inspire them that it's possible.
Here's how we inspire by our own testimonial.
If I can do it, you can do it.
Here's how else we inspire by others testimonial. If
they can do it, Mary, you can do it.
Getting people to see themselves better than they
are. Getting people to see themselves richer than
they are. Getting people to see themselves more
capable next year than they are this year. Getting
to see themselves in the future. To help both
your kids and your people, here's what you must learn
to do. Number one, help people to see
themselves as they are. If people have made mistakes,
they got to know it. You can't go on making
mistakes and hope to get better. You can't go on
making mistakes and hope to achieve. Mistakes have to
be corrected. And you've got to do it with
your children. Help them to see themselves as they
are. If they've messed up, here's what you've got
to say. You've messed up. But here's what's important
as a parent. Don't leave them in the mess.
Some parents, you know, tell their kids they've messed
up and then they leave them in the mess.
They don't paint a better picture. Here's what you
could become with just a couple of more changes.
Rather than this, here's what you could be.
So we must help our children see themselves as
they are. But here's the greatest gift. To help our
children see themselves better than they are. To
transport them not only past to see their mistakes,
but transport them to the future to see
their opportunity. To see the person they can become.
My mentor had that greatest gift to help me to
see myself better than I was. At first, it was
difficult to see. Then I started to believe. And that's
how I got here today. He said, one of these
things is that you walk into a room full of
people and you will hear some of them say, that's him,
that's the famous man. I said, well, that
could never happen to me. He said, trust me.
If you keep working hard on the
disciplines like you're doing right now, that'll happen.
You'll walk into a room full of people and
you'll hear one say, that's him, that's the famous man.
He saw it and he tried to get me to see
it. And now finally it's happened. I think when I walked
in here today, I think I heard someone say,
that's him, that's the famous man. It happened for me.
And if it can happen for me, it can
happen for you. Just master these skills to inspire.
Here's what else I learned. The skills
of building an organization. Learn to work with
the people who deserve it, not the people who
need it. You must be like life itself. Respond
to deserve, not to need. It doesn't say
if you need, you will have a harvest.
It doesn't say,
if you need a harvest, you'll have
a harvest. It's not what it says.
It says, if you plant, chances are
good you'll have a harvest. If you plant,
you will reap. Not if you need, you will reap.
So we must be like life itself. Respond to the
people who deserve it by planting, by taking the
first step. Even God himself says, if you move
toward me, I'll move toward you. That's the
condition. You move toward me, I'll move toward
you. He says, if you need, you'll have a harvest.
It's not what it says. If you plant, chances are good,
you'll have a harvest. It's not what it says.
If you plant, chances are good, you'll have a harvest.
That is the Almighty. Now he could also say,
you don't move, I don't move. You say, well,
that's arbitrary. Well, when you're God,
you can set it up that way.
Now, learn to work with the people who
deserve it, not the people who need it. Now,
here's what's the next step. Teach people how
to deserve your time. Teach people how to deserve
your attention. Tease people how to deserve a
phone call. Say, Mary, you just take this one
step and I take two steps. You
take two steps, I take five steps.
You don't step, I don't step. But this isn't
hard now. You step, I step. You respond, I respond.
You try, I try. You make a call, I back
you up. Right? Learn to teach people how to deserve your
time and your attention. Next, I learn to
work by group more than individual. Here's why. 80%
of the people do 20% of the business. So
20% of the people you can work with individually,
80% you have to work with by
group. But group is very powerful, less confrontational.
Then here's what's important for all of you
to learn as a sponsor, helping other people.
You can help a thousand, but you can't carry
three on your back. You can help a thousand,
but you can't carry three on your back. And
I'm sure all of you have already gotten that
experience, even though you've been here a short
time. Some people will try to get on,
but they can't. You're back. That's
where we got that expression. Get off.
That's where we got that. A guy discovered
somebody on his back and said, what? I can't
carry you. Get off. Now, if you're like some I
see here, you know, six foot four and you weigh 300
pounds, you might carry one. And if you
were really big enough, Kareem Abdul-Jabbar or something,
you might carry two.
You can't carry three. When babies are born,
they were not designed just to be carried.
Babies were not born to be carried all their life.
Someday you've got to try your legs. Someday
you've got to try your wings. Someday you've
got to try. Even if you fall down, you've
got to try because you can't just crawl around all
your life. You can't be carried all your life.
So as quickly as possible, you can help a thousand,
but you can't carry.
Three.
Next, don't expect the pear tree to bear apples.
I used to try to change everything. You can hang
apples on a pear tree. I'm telling you, it won't
help. You can put up a sign. This is an apple
tree. Sure enough, come the season, pears.
Here's what I learned. You cannot change people,
but they can change themselves. You cannot change
people, but they can change themselves.
Incredible.
Capital in your business isn't what matters. Okay,
it's not the money that buys you a future.
It's your skills that buy you a future. Money
and no skills and I'm telling you, you're still poor.
Money and no ambition, where are
you? Money and no courage, you're broke.
A little bit of money and a whole lot of
courage. That's all we need. I'm looking for people when I'm
recruiting back in those days and the money didn't
matter. What mattered to me was the money. What I
wanted to do was somebody's willingness,
somebody's ingenuity, somebody's willingness to try.
If they had a dollar to invest, that was plenty for
me. A dollar and some ambition and I can show you
how to get rich and it'll be one of the
classic stories of the company. I go to recruit somebody,
they say, I don't have any money. See, I've been
looking for you for six months. Let me show you
how to do it without any money. Because here's
the rules of capitalism. Jot this down. You can either
buy and sell or if you're in certain circumstances, you can
buy and sell. You can buy and sell and you can
sell and buy. If you've got ambition. Now, if
you haven't got ambition, we can't cure that and money
won't cure lack of ambition. But if you've got a
dollar and some ambition, I'll show you how to get
rich. And even if you don't have a dollar, I'll
show you how to get rich because you can sell
and buy. Somebody says, as soon as the
product arrives, I'll sell it. Then you don't understand.
You don't understand the magic of fortune. If you say,
I have to wait until it gets here to sell it.
And you probably don't understand the value of your
own story. Once I understood that, I knew I was
going to be wealthy. That's why right in the
beginning, I started giving big tips. I knew I
was going to be wealthy. Say, wow, this guy tips
like a rich man. That's right. He tips like a rich
man. Even in the beginning, I tipped like a rich
man because I knew I was going to be rich.
Isn't this fun?
Yes.
So jot these phrases down as I close. Number one,
the greatest value in life is not a bank account. The
greatest value in life is not a car, a home to
live in. The greatest value in life is this. Make a
note, living a good life. In the midst of all of
our achieving and recruiting and building and
growing, helping other people, being a part of
society and the country and the world, being all
of this stuff, here's what you must figure out all
of your life, how to continually live your life. And
I'm going to tell you how to do that. I'm going
to tell you how to live a good life. So let
me give you my short list. I'll cover the long list the
next time I see you. Here's the short list
on a good life. Number one, productivity. If you don't
produce, you won't be happy. Here's number two,
good friends. The greatest support system in the
world is good friends. You got to work on
that. Don't be careless here. Friends are those wonderful
people who know all about you and still like you.
Here's next, spirituality. I'm not asking you to be
a believer. I am a believer that humans are more
than an advanced form of the animal kingdom. I'm
a believer that we're a special creation. I don't
ask you to be a believer, but here's what I do
ask. If you are a believer, here's what you must do.
Study, practice, and teach. Whatever's valuable to you,
study, practice, and teach. Repeat it after me
now. Again, study, practice, and teach.
Here's why. It builds the foundation that builds
the country, that builds the nation, that helps us
to compete among the nations of the world in
the 21st century. And this is one of those subjects,
to study, practice, and teach. Next,
my parents taught, don't miss anything.
Don't miss the game. Don't miss the performance.
Don't miss the show, the movie. Don't miss the
words.
We're all inspired by the words. Elton John says
she lived her life like a candle in the wind,
never knowing who to cling to when the rain
set in. You can't miss those lyrics. You can't miss
the music. You can't miss the songs that nourish
the soul. You can't describe how brief and fragile
life is much better than that. George Harrison,
one of the Beatles, sings, if not for you,
the winter would hold no spring. Couldn't hear a robin
sing. I just wouldn't have a clue if not for you.
Wow. You've got to remember the words,
the words that reflect the experience. Barbara Streisand
sings, it used to be so natural to talk
about forever, but used to be's don't count anymore.
They just lay on the floor till we sweep
them away. You don't sing me love songs. You don't
say you need me, and you don't bring me flowers.
You don't say you need me, and you don't
bring me flowers anymore. Illustrative of all of our
experiences. Winston Churchill said the truth
is incontrovertible. Malice may attack it and
ignorance may deride it, but in the end, there
it is. You've got to use that. Feast on someone
else's comments. Because see, you could stay
up all night and not think of that.
I'm asking you to do your research. I'm
asking you, don't miss anything. Don't miss the play.
Don't miss the play. Don't miss the play. Don't miss
the play. Don't miss the play. Don't miss the play.
When my father was 93, just before he died, if you
would have called him at 10, 30, 11 o'clock at night,
he wouldn't be home. He's at the rodeo. And
he's watching the kids play softball. He's at church.
He's watching the concert somewhere every night.
My parents taught me that. Don't miss anything.
Even little small things, don't miss. Big
things, don't miss. Don't miss, don't miss.
It's part of living a good life. Here's why.
Jot this phrase down. It'll serve you well forever.
If you live well, you will earn well. If you
live well, it'll show up in the texture of your voice.
If you live well, it'll show up in your face.
If you live well, it'll show up in the magnetism of
your personality. If you live well. So don't miss
the nourishment of all the things around you that
could help you live a good life. Next is the
inner circle. Take care of them, they'll take care of you.
Inspire them, they will inspire you. Nothing more
valuable than the inner circle. That's where the
power to conquer the world comes from. That's
where the power to conquer the world comes from.
The inner circle. If a father walks out of the
house and he can still all day long feel his
daughter's kiss on his face, he's a powerful
man. Nourishment of the inner circle is so incredible.
If a husband walks out of the house and all
day long he feels the imprint of his wife's arms
around his body, he's invincible. Who can touch
him? One person caring for another, the old prophet
said, is the greatest. There's many virtues and
values, but the greatest is love. One person
caring for another. Better to live than to live in
a tent. Better to live than to live in a tent.
Better to live than to live in a tent.
On the other hand, you can't live with someone
you love than to live in a mansion yourself.
People caring for people. And especially that inner
circle where the power is so magnificent that if
you draw from it, if you nourish it, and then
it nourishes you. Now here's my last comment. Ask for
God's help. We could all use a little help. But my
whole seminar was what you can do. A man took a
rock pile, turned it into a fabulous garden. Somebody
came and saw it and said, you know, you
and the good Lord have this fabulous garden
here. The gardener said, I understand your point,
but you should have seen it a few
years ago when God had it all by himself.
So we do play a part. So make this the
last note now. We have a chance as human beings to
participate in the miracle process. We have a
chance as human beings to participate in the
miracle process. And you can go do that every
day as often as you wish. Changing somebody's life.
Rescuing somebody from oblivion.
Building an organization second to none so that
your name will appear in many people's testimonial.
And that's why I came today. So that by chance,
I don't need the money. That's not why I'm here.
I take the money, but I don't need the
money. But here's why I'm here. By chance, perhaps,
if I've come along at the right time. I don't know
what time this is for you, but if I've come along
at the right time, just maybe a week from now,
a month from now, a year from now, five years from
now, you might say, Jim Rohn came by and gave
us a little piece of information that started me down
the road. Here's what I'm going to do. I'm going to do
it. I'm going to do it. I'm going to do it. I'm
going to do it. I'm going to do it. I'm going to
do it. I'm going to do it. I'm going to do it.
Here's what's happened to me. And my name
might appear in your testimonial. Now, here's the drama
as we finish. How many of you have my name in
your notes? Here's the part of the drama then. I go
with you. When we all leave here and the lights
are out and the place is dark, I go with you
because you've taken my notes and hopefully some of
the spirit, some of the stuff I had besides
just the notes. So I go with all of you.
But here's the big drama. All of you go with me.
See, that's so unbelievable. So as I leave here,
I promise not to leave you behind. I will take
you with me in my thoughts
and in my heart. God bless.
Thank you for listening to Building
Your Network Marketing Business with Jim Rohn.
To receive more information on
Jim Rohn's speaking schedule and products,
please visit his website at www.jimrohn.com.
Thanks again for listening and make it
your best year ever. Here's to your success.
Thank you.